I'm home. The shoes. Shoes. Remove the shoes
（深井ほなみ）　ただいま。 （深井武広）　塩　塩　まいて入れよ。
I said remove the shoes Ok..ok..ok
ほら　塩だって。 （深井千秋）　はいはいはい…。
You also. Remove the shoes.
はい　お前も　お前も。
Ah! That looks delicious~ Ah! That's my crepe.
あ～　おいしそう～！ あっ　ミルクレープ　俺のだからな。
When that time comes~ What about when that time comes?
（ほなみ）　私ん時はさ～。 （深井平太）　「私ん時」って？
For my funeral, I absolutely don't want anything on my face.
私のお葬式　絶対　あんなに 化粧しないでもらいたい。
I don't like retouching with powder
嫌だよ　あれ　粉ふいてんだもん。
Me too. I don't want my face painted white when I turn 94
ハハ　確かに　９４歳のじいさんに あの白塗りは　ないよな。
You guys must not put anything to my face when that time comes! Ok?
あんた達　私ん時は 絶対　厚塗りしないでよね。
Then what about make-up? I hate that also. I hate that more!
（千秋）　じゃあ　すっぴんね。 （ほなみ）　嫌だよ　それ　もっと嫌。
First of, take out the dullness off my face by using cream
私のさ　まずね　くすみ取りの クリームあるじゃない→
Look, I'm always using cream. So just apply a little bit of it...
ほら　いつも使ってるやつね あれを　ちょっと塗って…。
What if Kyuto is not here..
＜もし　Ｑ１０が いなくなってしまったら→
I wonder will I go hungry
それでも 腹が　へったりするんだろうか＞
Will I be able to eat well
＜ご飯　食べて　「もう　食えねえ」 とか　いうんだろうか＞
Ah! By the way Heita
（武広）　あっ　そうだ　平太。
Isao said that I'll give this to you. Hmm?
イサオが　これ お前に渡してくれって。 え？
He said that this was the book you liked.
（武広） お前が好きだった絵本だって。
Ah! This brings back the memories!
あ～　懐かしい！
“Just like men and organ. The Hippopotamus was able to produce a sound”.
「は　をおすと　オルガンみたいに おとを　だす　カバがいました」。
What's wrong?
（武広）　どうした？
N..nothing. Thank you
あっ　いや　ありがとう。 うん。
Ok. Thank him by sending email
メールでいいから　お礼いっとけよ。
Alright. Let's eat then!
よし　じゃ　食べよっか。
Whoa!
（中尾）　ひぃ～！
((That's why I'm telling you, she isn't your belonging))
（月子）((だからって あんたのものじゃないからね))
((Q10 belongs to us))
((Ｑ１０は 私達のものなんだからね))
I've decided that I'll come to school daily
（月子）　私　今日から毎日 学校に来ることにしたから。
Ok
そう。
So that I'm able to see Fukai-kun everyday.
深井君に　毎日　会いたいから。
Whoa~~
（生徒達）　おぉ～。
Did I annoy you? I don't care.
迷惑かな？ 別に。
What I'm saying is I want you to go out with me.
それは　私と付き合ってもいい っていう意味？
I don't want to.
いや　違うでしょ。
You're no fun at all
面白くない。
You're reaction is definitely boring
そのリアクション 全然　面白くない。
As for me..
私としては→
I'm liking you more when you are upset
もっと取り乱した 深井君が好きなんだよね。
Don't touch her!
触んな！
Fujino is sick and she's resting
（小川　訪）　富士野さ これ以上　休むと　ヤバイんだよ。
I'm really concerned about her. I'm supposed to go and visit her
せっかく　本人 出る気になってるのにさ→
I don't like it when you're getting depressed
お前に嫌われたって 落ち込んじゃってさ。
Sensei Hm?
先生。 ん？
I was not talking about what happens to Fujino. I am talking about Kyuto and Fujino Tsukiko
違うんです　富士野は 富士野月子は　Ｑ１０の…。
((Don't talk about me to other people))
（月子）((私のこと ひとに　いわないでね))
((If you do, I'm going to withdraw Q10 from you))
((いうと Ｑ１０は　即　撤収だから))
What happened between Fujino Tsukiko and Q10? Well..
富士野とＱ１０　何かあったの？ いや…。
Anyway, from now on..
まぁ　とにかくさ　お前から→
If Fujino Tsukiko says something, tell me about it.
富士野に　ひと言 何か　いってやってくんねえかな。
It's not that you hate her for no reason... I hate her
「別に嫌ってるわけじゃ　ない」…。 嫌いです。
Huh?
は？
I don't like Fujino Tsukiko Eh?
富士野月子は　嫌いです。 え？
Hey! Wait!
おい　ちょっと！
I don't know what's going on in here...
何があったか知んないけど→
Jeezz grow up a little bit
もうちょっと大人になろうよ～。
Since, I am a Tsukiko
私　「月子」だから→
call me Runa-chan
「ルナちゃん」って 呼んでくれるかな？
Don't tell me that!
そんなこと！
Uwaa~~ Stop it!
うわ～～　やめろ～～！
This school is interesting
学校って　面白い所ですね。
You might want to have the lucky bag this New Year
（柳）　ハハ… お正月の福袋みたいなもんよ。
I have packed a lot of things in that bag with effort
無理やり　いろんなの 詰め込まれてる　あれ。
Doing such things is what makes it enjoyable
でも　それが楽しかったりしてね フフ。
Did you apply something?
何か塗ってる？
Smells like medicine...no..it's different.
薬みたい…　いや　違う。
My skin is weak. I applied an important topical cream
私　肌が弱くって 塗り薬　欠かせないんです。
Really?
そう。
"Just like men and organ, the hippopotamus was able to produce a sound"
（深井の声） 「は　をおすと　オルガンみたいに おとを　だす　カバがいました。
It's unusual that men and organ can be compared to hippopotamus' sound..
は　をおすと　おとの　でるカバは めずらしかったので→
Everybody wanted to have that one. That is why everybody is fighting.
みんなが　ほしがりました そのことで　けんかになり→
In the end, nobody was able to get it
とうとう　くにどうしの せんそうに　なってしまいました」。
That's how the story goes
こんな話だったんだ。
"For Kenta, he folded the hippopotamus organ into a shape of a bag"
（Ｑ１０）　「ケンタは　オルガンカバを カバンの　かたちに　たたむと→
"Just like the suitcase, then he hurriedly escaped"
スタコラサッサッと にげてゆきました」。
And then?
うん　それで？
“He was successful. He was successful”.
「めでたし　めでたし」。
Huh? That's the end? Whoa~ You're right
えっ　これで終わり？ うわ　ホントだ。
What is this? The problem was not solved
何これ 全然　解決してねえじゃん。
But he escaped
でも　逃げました。
It won't stop if he continues to ran away... Later on, for sure somebody will come after him
そんなの　逃げきれるわけない… 追っ手が来て　絶対→
Even so, someone has decided to bring it back... If that happens, then he has to escape again
連れ戻されるに決まってる…。 そしたら　また逃げます。
Even so he keeps doing that, there will be another one who will get it
だから　それでも また　絶対　捕まんだって。
If that happens, he has to escape again No...even though...
そしたら　また逃げます。 いや　だから…。
I see
分かった。
In other words, the one who has the guts wins the fight right?
つまり　根性があるほうが 勝ちってことだな？
Hey. Do you know which way is Osaka?
ねぇ　大阪　どっち？
Umm... eh? Osaka?!
あぁ…　え…　大阪!?
Eh? well...
え？　いや　まぁ→
Anyway, its there in the West
とりあえず 西は　あっちですけど。
Thank you. Eh? Eh? You'll really go there? By that...
ありがとう。 え？　え？　本当に　それで…。
Eh~~?
え～？
If we have to follow this familiar road ..
＜この見慣れた道を行けば→
I really have no idea where it will lead us
全然知らない場所に　たどり着く＞
(( I have decided that I'll come to school everyday))
（月子）((私　今日から毎日 学校に来ることにしたから))
(( Q10 belongs to us ))
((Ｑ１０は 私達のものなんだからね))
If I have the guts to do it. For sure we'll be able to get there
＜俺に根性があれば きっと　たどり着く＞
Kyuto
Ｑ１０。
Let's run away
逃げよう。
Where to?
どこへですか？
Somewhere far away.
どっか　遠いとこ。
If I'm able to do it, I won't feel uneasy anymore
＜でき得るならば 不安の　かけらもない所＞
What are you doing?
何やってんの？
I'm looking for the most important thing
一番大事なものを 探しているのだよ？
The most important thing? Eh? What is that?
一番大事なもの？ え　何？　何それ。
What is that thing that I'm supposed to be looking for?
それが何なのか 探しているのだよ？
I don't know what are you looking for
あ　じゃあ　何か分からなくて 探してんだ？
What is the most important for you sensei?
先生は　何が大事かな？
Hmm... what could it be..
え？　俺　何だろう。
Well, it will be difficult for me if this disappears... This phone
まぁ　なくなったら困る… それは　もう　ケータイかな。
Cellphones are convenient. Ok. I know that
ケータイは　便利でありんす。 よく分かってるじゃん。
Convenient! The way you use it is completely wrong.
便利！ 全然　使い方　違うから　それ。
Hey! Tell her that's weird
ちょっと　変なこと教えないでよ。
You're the boss here. It's better if you're the one saying
（小川しげ）　だって 長さが　ちょうどいいんだもん。
That's the problem. Cellphone has a lot of use.
そういう問題じゃ　ないでしょう。 ケータイは　もっと便利だよ。
It can be a chair Yup. Cute
イス。 うん　かわいいね。
But, that is not how you use it. Q-chan, the most important thing is...
でも　これ　全然違うから。 Ｑちゃん　一番大事なのはね→
Memory of family
家族の思い出。
Don't show her something that is biased...
だから　こういう　偏ったこと 教えちゃダメだっつってる…。
Where have I been biased?
どこが偏ってんのよ。
Don't tell her about general things
もっと　一般的なこと 教えないとダメじゃん。
Then, what is the most important thing to you?
じゃあ　何よ　一番大事なもの。
Love
愛？
Uwaah! That's disgusting! right?
うわっ　気持悪ぃ　ねぇ。
Gefu. Gefu? What is that?
ゲフ。 「ゲフ」って　何それ。
Here. These are 90 pieces of willows
これ　柳教授に。
Give this as hospitality gift to the owner of the lodge you are going to stay
泊めてもらうんだから 手土産ぐらい持って行きなさい。
Then, I'll... What is that baggage?
じゃあ　俺…。 （千秋）　何？　その荷物。
He's going for a sleep over today.
今日　泊まりなんだって。
You're sleeping over to that good friend of yours? Yes of course
そんな　仲のいい友達いたっけ？ いるよ。
Then, I have to go. Ok~~
じゃあ　いってきます。 （ほなみ）　は～い。
Hey hey! Come here.. Eh? Why?
おいおいおい　ちょっと来い…。 え？　何？
For quite some time, I have always hidden this for the sake of someone else
何かの時のために　俺が　ず～っと ひた隠しに　隠して来たものだ。
"The dull life" No.1 manga
「どんづまり人生」。 万が一→
In page 78, an unlikely event happens. "Seven tumbles, eight occurs" ("Seven tumbles, eight occurs": is a proverb that means rising after a fall")
万が一の時のための　７８ページ 「七転び八起き」だ。
Ha? I understand what everyone is trying to say
は？ 分かってる　皆までいうな。
For them, a man should not say "Do you have something that I can spend?"
男ってのは　ひとには　いえない 出費ってもんが　あるんだよ。
Don't hesitate to tell me
遠慮なく　取っとけ。
What is this?
これ　何？
That's money You don't know what that is?
「何」ってお金じゃん お前　知らないの？
I don't know
知らない。
Huh? That's 10,000 yen bill...You really don't know?
えっ １万円札じゃん　えっ　マジで？
Why do we have to change clothes?
なぜ　着替えるのですか？
Wearing uniform makes us stand out
制服じゃ　目立つ。
I was told to give this 90 pcs willow as a hospitality gift
柳教授に手土産を渡すよう いわれましただよ。
That's good. I'll pass it to them Then, we won't be found out
いいんだよ　こんなの渡さなくて ウソが　バレんだろ。
It'll be troublesome if we'll be found out
ウソが　バレると困る。
It's a secret that we went out
出かけんのは みんなには秘密だから。
Alrighty
よいしょ。
This is not the place for us to go
２人で ここじゃ　ない　遠い所へ行く。
Then, we will be successful?
そこで　２人は めでたし　めでたしですか？
Sorry. I think that will be impossible
ごめん　それは無理。
Right now, it's impossible for me
今の俺には無理なんだ。
I found a place where Kyuto can hide and won't be found out
見つからない所に　Ｑ１０を隠す。
Right now, I don't know for how long you must hide
今　できんの　そんくらいなんだ。
But, one thing is for sure, I will definitely pick you up
でも　必ず迎えに行くから。
By all means, I will definitely find a way that you'll be in front of me always
何とか自分の力で　Ｑ１０のこと かくまえるようになったら　必ず。
I promise
約束する。
Don't make promises
約束は　しません。
All this time, I believe in Heita
いつ　いかなる時も Ｑ１０は　平太を信じます。
What?　What?
（恵美子）　何？　何？
What is it?
何？
Oh..well..
（影山）　あっ　いや…。
I thought you agree to my decision Yup..
別れるって決めたじゃん。 うん。
So..
いや　だから…→
For the last time, I want to make a movie.. Kawai's movie.
最後に映画　撮りたいんだよ 河合の映画。
If you don't like it, I'll stop from there.
嫌だったら　やめるから。
But. I want to take this chance
でも 俺　撮っておきたいんだよね。
I know that I'm not cool
全然カッコよくないんだけどさ→
I'm slowly becoming worst But I have high regard to the 3 of us
ぐずぐずで　最低の 高３の俺達なんだけど→
But still, I want to take this chance
でも　撮っておきたいんだよ。
Hmmm..
う～ん…。
Then..
だったら…。
Can you at least make a movie that has happy moments?
せめて　映画だけでも 幸せに撮ってくれるかな？
I want to watch something like "We were going so well"
「私達　うまく行って こうなりました！」みたいな。
"We were so happy!" Something like that
「こんなに幸せになりました！」 みたいな。
Ok. Sure. Let's do that.
うん　いいよ　それ撮ろう　うん。
Ok~~ Start!
よ～い　スタート！
Alright.
よし。
“For the sake of the baby, eat a lot ok?"
「赤ちゃんのために いっぱい食べな？」。
“Yup. Delicious~”.
「うん　おいしい！　フフっ」。
“Ah! Look! There's a cream…”.
「あっ　ほら　クリームが…」。
Well ~ that's just...
いや～　ちょっと　それは…。
W..wait! What are you doing?! Jezz! Sorry! Sorry!
ちょっ！　何してんのよ　もう！ ごめん　ごめん！
Ah! Don't do that! That stairs is dangerous for you!
（影山）　「あ～　ダメだよ！ 階段　危ないんだから」。
Since it's dangerous, I have to carry you then
「あっ　危ないから 俺が　抱っこしてあげるよ」。
Eh? Carry?!
えっ　抱っこ!?
W..wait! I'm heavy! You can't carry me! It's ok! It's ok! You're not heavy...
ちょ…　重いから　無理だって！ 大丈夫　大丈夫！　重くない…。
We're going to fall! We're falling!
落ちる　落ちる！ あ～　ちょっ　ちょっ…！
Cut! Cut! Cut!
カット　カット　カット！
Sorry! Let's do again the stairs scene
ごめん！ もう一回　階段のとこから。
a child is already born! Look~~ Next, we'll do it properly! ok?
もう生まれちゃったよ　ほら。 次は絶対　ちゃんとやるから　ね？
Shotgun wedding? You have a loud voice
できちゃった婚？ （岸本）　あんまり大きな声じゃ→
Don't say anything. Congratulations!
いえないんだけどさ。 そりゃ　おめでとうございます。
I'm not happy about it
だから めでたくなんかないんだって。
But... Somehow, I'm a nasty person
いや　だって…。 何か　いけ好かない男でさ。
Why would my daughter go to that kind of man?
娘のヤツ 何で　あんな男に行くかね？
There's nothing you can do about forced marriage
できちゃったもんは しょうがないじゃないですか。
Then she said when she gives birth
それより　産んじゃって→
she will really try hard to hide her embarrassment. She hated that feeling
なし崩しにしようっていう 根性が気に食わないんだよ。
Stop it! I don't understand the feeling
治まんないよ　気持が。
So, when will she give birth?
で　いつ生まれるんですか？
It's either today or tomorrow
今日か明日。
Eh?! Aren't you going to her now
え～!? もう　すぐじゃないですか！
I don't feel like celebrating with them but It'll be ok right?
スッキリ　気分よく　祝ってやれば いいんだろうけどさ。
Jeez...I detest it!!
もう…　憎い～！
W..wait...Principal! Principal!
ちょっ…　校長！　校長！
Where are we going to escape?
どこに逃げるのかな？
For the meantime, over there?
う～ん　とりあえず　あっち？
Suitcase!
スタコラサッサ～ スタコラサッサ～。
There's a woman who's carrying a lot of baggage
女の人が たくさん荷物を持っています。
Oh! Thank you very much
あっ　どうもありがとう。
Kyuto is even a woman right?
Ｑ１０だって女の人でしょ？
Water!　Water!
水！　水！　水！
It's a sea! Sea!
海だよ　海！　海！
Uwa! Uwa!
うわ～！　うわ～！　うわ～！ [TEL]（カメラのシャッター音）
Sea ~! You'll get wet
海～！ 濡れんなよ？
Why did you bring that with you?
何で　こんなの持って来たの？
I am waiting for the most important thing to come...
一番大事なものだけを 待って来るよう→
Just like what you said
平太が　いいました。
Well...I did say that but why album?
まぁ　いったけどさ 何で　アルバム？
By the way, who owns this?
ってか　誰だよ　これ。
Ogawa sensei's grandmother Is that so?
小川先生の　おじいさんだよ。 そうなの？
Now that you mention it. I don't know her
…っていわれてもな 知らない人だしなぁ。
Oh~ This is funny. This album
面白いんだ？　こんなのが。
She is the person who gave birth to this person
この人を産んだのが　この人で→
This person is this person's older sister
この人のお姉さんが　この人で→
This onesan gave birth to this child...
このお姉さんが産んだのが この子供で…。
Hmm~
ふ～ん。
Eventually people will die
人は　死ぬけれど続いて行く。
Even you Heita, will die, but the children are left behind
平太が死んでも子供が残る。
Children?
子供？
Somehow, a child...
子供なんか…→
I don't need it
いらないよ。
It's alive
生きてる。
It's dead
死んでる。
Sorry.
すんません。
I'm sorry about that~
≪すいませ～ん！≫
Thank you very much
どうも　ありがとうございました。
It's alright Don't cry anymore.
ほら　大丈夫？ もう　泣かなくていいよ。
I'm hungry
腹へったなぁ。
By the way, I'm going to charge you now ok?
そうだ　Ｑ１０も 充電しといたほうがいいよな。
Puff
パフ。 うん。
Excuse me~ Yes~
すんません。 はい。
Can I use your source of electricity? Ok.. Anytime.
電源　借りてもいいですか？ はい　どうぞ。
Excuse me
すいません　よいしょ。
Where is the charger?
あれ？　充電するやつは？
I forgot to bring it
持って来ていません。
Eh? Why?
え？　何で？
Because you said that I have to bring only the most important thing
「一番大事なものだけを 持って行く」といいました。
Yeah I said that, but that one is important right? That charger is important right?
いや　いったけどさ　大事でしょ？ 充電するやつ　ねぇ。
Eh? You didn't bring it? Really?
えっ　持って来てないの？ マジで？
Puff
パフ。
Eh~~
え～！
Y..you really have done it... Ehhh
いやっ　うわっ　やらかしてる…
Yes~
（ノック） は～い。
Oh!
（柳）　おっ。
You look good! Hai
元気そうじゃん。 （藤丘）　はい。
Well...here.. Hm?
あの　これ…。 ん？
It's the first time that I baked. It's a bread.
俺が初めて焼かしてもらった パンです。
Eh? You really baked this?
え？　これ　藤丘君が焼いたの？
That's awesome
すごいじゃん。
During that time when you gave us bread, I wasn't able to pull it well...
教授から　あの時　もらったパンが まだ　ぬくかったんで…。
Share it among yourselves!
((分け前！　君達の分！))
Therefore, I want to make something warm..
だから　俺も まだ温かいうちにって。
Ahhh~~
あぁ～　ハハっ。
You guys! What are you doing? Get out from there
こら　何やってんだよ 授業　出ろよ。
Jeezz
ったく。
What are you doing there?
何してんすか？
The scent of tomorrow~
ん～　明日のにおいがする。
Huh?
はぁ？
Pan? Oh! Pan!
パン？　おぉ　パン。
That is the first bread that Fujioka baked
それね 藤丘君が初めて焼いたパン。
Really?
あっ　そうなんですか。
Would you like to smell the scent of tomorrow?
明日のにおい　しませんか？
Yeah
うん。 ね。
This time, Yamakawa-san is going to take care of his family
（店長の声）　このたび　山川さんが ご家族の介護に→
He will devote his life doing that. He is retiring from work right now
専念されたいということで 退職されることになりました。
Well aside from that news,
まぁ その代わりといっては何ですが→
We have a new worker that will work hard from now on
フレッシュな藤丘君が入って 頑張ってくれることになりました。
Depression is far from over
不況は　まだまだ続きます。
We have to work together! Let's do our best! Cheers!
みんな　一丸となって 頑張りましょう　乾杯！
Thank you for your hard work
（拍手） お疲れ！
Do your best
（山川）　頑張れよ。 はい。
Kyuto is sleepy now
Ｑ１０　眠くなりました。
Uwa~~ w..wai..wait a minute
う～わ…　ちょ　ちょっと待って。
Oh! They're madly in love!
うぉ～　熱愛　熱愛！ ヒュ～　ヒュ～！
They're so madly in love!
超熱愛！
You're can't be serious...
マジか…。
It's impossible for me to take you back home
ホントに　連れて帰るの 無理になっちゃったよ。
This is the only place we can go
この町に置いて行くしかないよ。
I'm sorry..I'm so sorry
ごめん…　ごめんね。
Grandma is here~~
「おばあちゃんですよ～」。
Hurry and come out already~
「早く出ておいでよ～」。
I'm going to wait for you~
（しげ）　「待ってるよ～」。
Grandpa, here is your grandchild~
「おとうさん　孫でちゅよ～」。
Babu babu babu babu..
「バブバブ　バブバブ…」。
Mama~ Mama~
「ママ　マ～マ　ママ　ママ」。
Mother-in law! Mom!
「お義母さん！」。 「お母さん！」。
I don't want you to die~
「死んじゃ嫌だよ～」。
Dried frozen tofu...
「高野豆腐…→
Soak it in water...
水に　つけたまま…→
haaaahh... there...fore...
ハァハァ…　だか…　ら…」。
What is it Ok! Cut! Cut!
何よう。 （影山）　はい　カット　カット！
Ok! Again!
はい　回った！
Start!
（影山）　よ～い　スタート。
Bye! bye!
「じゃあ　バイバ～イ！」。
Bye bye!
「バイバ～イ」。
Damn it...what will I do?
参った…　どうしよう。
Are you looking for a boat?
≪船を探しているのかい？≫
Well….
あっ　いや…。
That one is not working Nobody is using that one
そりゃダメだよ 誰も使わなくなっちゃってね。
That was not used for so many years It's terrible
何年も　ほったらかしてるから もう　ひどいんだ。
So you want to ride a boat?
船に乗りたかったらね→
Ask somebody over there.
ほら　あっち　あそこへ行って頼め。
This is strange..
不思議だよな…。
Today isn't over yet,
まだ　一日も経ってないのに→
Just like at home or in school..
家のこととか　学校のこととか→
Just like the old times.
すっげぇ昔みたいに思える。
Shall I go back?
俺　戻れんのかな？
I just felt that I wanted to go back
何か　戻れない気するよ。
Kyuto cannot go back...
戻っても　Ｑ１０　いないし…。
I promise. I'm going to see you again
また会おうな　約束な。
I'll call Dr. Suzuki! Ok!
≪スズキ先生　コールして！≫ ≪はい！≫
7-8-9-10!
…７・８・９・１０！
Give epinephrine! Hai!
（医師）　≪エピネフリン　追加して！≫ ≪はい！≫
I'm sorry. I'll go home now
（民子）　ごめん　今日は帰るね。
Stay.
（久保）　いて。
Kawatani-san, the doctor wanted to talk to you. This way please.
川谷さん　先生の お話がありますので　こちらへ。
Ah..ok
あ…　はい。
What the doctor is about to say is..
「先生の話」っていうのはさ→
“This is the last time that you can see the patient. This is the time you'll be together.."
「最期に会わせたい人は 何時頃　集まるのか」→
"But, during that time that he's brain dead. Will it be ok for you if we remove the the machine that supports him"
「その時　機械　外しますけど いいですね」って→
He's about to say like that.
そういうこと　いわれるらしい。
It's useless already
もうダメなんだよ。
It's probably no use.
多分　もうダメ。
What do you know about that person?
知ってる人なんだ？
He's the person who I have occasionally talk to.
時々　話す人。
“It's just like working out"..
「筋トレだ」とかいって→
He's carrying the IV stand as he climbs the stairs up and down.
点滴　持ったまま 階段　上り下りしてさ。
Oh! Don't tell the doctor about this ok?
（川谷）((おぉ　先生には内緒な))
I understand his feelings. I can't believe that he died
（久保の声）　見た感じ 全然　死にそうじゃなくてさ。
I want to go back to Shaba as soon as possible. I want to walk to that bridge again
((早くシャバに戻りてぇ 戻って　橋　造りてぇ))
We make bridges. Look.
((俺　橋　造ってんの　ほら))
Heh~
（久保）((へぇ～))
I'm not married and I don't have children. But here I am making bridges.
((結婚もせず　子供もつくらず 橋ばっかり造ってさ))
Is it good? To have this kind of life?
((いいのかな？　こんな人生))
Whatever~ This guy right here is good as it is.
((まぁ　いっか！　いいよな こんなヤツ　いたってさ))
Yes you are
((はい))
Those were..
（久保の声）　それが→
the last words that I heard from him
俺が聞いた　最後の言葉。
“Whatever~"
「まぁ　いっか→
"This guy here is good as it is"
いいよな こんなヤツが　いたってさ」。
Uwa!
うわっ！
Excuse me!
すいません！
Hello! Is there anyone out there?
すいません！　誰か　いませんか？
Sorry for being late!
遅くなって　すいません！
What's the event for today?
今日のイベントって 何だったんですか？
Ah! I understand! That one!
あ～！　分かった！　あれだ。
Can I say something first?
あっ　えっ 僕から　先　いっていいですか？
Go ahead
どうぞ。
I'd like to say a story that happened when I was still a student
あれは　僕が　まだ学生だった頃の 話なんですけどね→
In our neighborhood, there is a rumor that happened at night
家の近所に 夜になると　必ず出るって噂の→
I saw a tunnel...
トンネルがあったんですよ…。
Why is there a candle in a bread (pan)?
何で　パンに ローソク刺してんですか？
I think it doesn't matter whether its on a cake or a pan
あっ　ケーキもパンも 似たようなもんかなって思って。
Aa.. eh? Then..
あぁ　あっ　え？　じゃあ→
It is like putting a candle on a real cake, right? Yup
ホントだったら　これ　ケーキに ローソクだったんですね？ はい。
I see..
なるほどね。
Huh? Is it perhaps, today's event is your birthday?
えっ？　もしかして その　イベントって　誕生日？
Yes. Today is my birthday~
はい　私の誕生日で～す。
No way! Why didn't you tell me beforehand?
ウソ～！　もう何で　それ 先　いってくんないんですか？
I should have prepared a present for you!
だったら プレゼントも用意したのに！
What is your gift for me?
何くれるつもりだったんですか？
Eh? A~ Well...
えっ？　あ～　いや いや　だから　あの…→
Necklace or flowers perhaps
ネックレス的なやつとか あっ　いや　花かな？　花。
Aa..
あぁ…。
What I want is...
私が欲しいのは…。
Yes?
はい。
A word.
言葉です。
Word??
言葉？
Will you write down for me? Words.
くれませんか？　言葉。
Haa
はぁ。
You're daughter will give birth to a child
（占い師）　娘さんが産む子供は→
It is a destiny wherein you will have a deep connection with
あなたと深～い因縁があります。
What do you mean?
…といいますと？
You got married twice right? Yes!
あなた　再婚ですね？ はい。
You're first wife was sick. Hence she died at young age!
最初の奥さんは 若くして病気で亡くなられた！
Yes! You're right!
はい！　そうです。
Now, the child that you're recent wife gave birth to..
今度　生まれる　お子さんは→
She will give birth to a child that is the reincarnation of your first wife
その奥様の生まれ変わりです。
Oh well...
あっ　いや～…。
A reincarnation of Mitsuko?
ミツコの生まれ変わり？
Here it is..
じゃあ　これ。
You're happy? Yes! I'm very happy
喜んでもらえました？ はい　とっても。
Well.. I'm glad...
いやぁ　よかった…。
That's not the one.. Here's the one.. That's not the one..
あ　あっ　違う　こっちだ あの　違った…。
"Henshin Reset" This is nice!
「ヘンシン　リセット」 いいですね！
When I was in elementary, I thought that was a gag! Gag!
いや～　それ　あの　小学校の時に 考えた　ギャグなんですよ　ギャグ。
In other words... "Hen..shin! reset!"
つまり…　「ヘンシン！　リセット」 何つって。
Although I want to transform ..
あの　変身するんですけど→
I eventually went back to the way I was and I noticed that nothing is changed
結局　元に戻って 何も変わらないみたいな。
But when you say "reset" that happens for about 0.2 second..
でも「リセット」っていってる間の ０．２秒くらいは→
And then will transform back where everyone can't see it with their own eyes
変身してるんですよね みんなの目には見えないけど。
Well... I guess so..
まぁまぁまぁ　そうですかね…。
Henshin...risetto (reset)
ヘンシン！　リセット　アハハ。 リセット　ハハハ。
This is good! Is it good?
いいです　これ。 いいっすか　いいっすか？
This is embarrassing
ちょっと恥ずかしいな。
Why did I give her that?
何で　あっち　渡すかなぁ？
My life right now is just like a continuation of a drama series
俺の人生 「今のなし」の連続だよな。
Happy birthday to me~~
♪～　タ～ンタ　タンタンタンタン
Yes?
はい。
Eh? Is that so?
え？　そうですか。
Then, we're going to collect Q10 back?
じゃあ　Ｑ１０は　回収ですか？
I understand. The preparation for withdrawal will start tomorrow
分かりました 明日から撤収準備　始めます。
My mission has ended
（月子）　任務は終わりだってよ。
Let's go home.
帰るよ。
"Welcome back home"
[ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵｶﾒﾗ]　「おかえりなさい」。
"Welcome back home!"
[ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵｶﾒﾗ]　「おかえりなさい！」。
"Hmph. Welcome back"
[ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵｶﾒﾗ]　「ん　おかえり」。
"Welcome back home" (Imitating Q10)
[ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵｶﾒﾗ]（Ｑ１０のモノマネ） 「おかえりなさい」。
"That's like Kyuto"
（影山）　それ　久戸じゃん。 [ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵｶﾒﾗ] フフフ…。
One more time. Ok~~
（影山）　はい　もう一回。 [ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵｶﾒﾗ] （恵美子）　は～い。
"Welcome back home"
[ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵｶﾒﾗ]（恵美子）　「おかえりなさいっ」。
"Welcome back home!"
[ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵｶﾒﾗ]（恵美子）　「おかえりなさい！」。
That light is nostalgic,
＜それは　懐かしい光だった＞
I've seen that light before I was born.
＜生まれる前に 見たことがあるような→
< It was a warm and gentle light >
温かで　優しい光だった＞
Aahh~ Nice meeting you I'm your grandfather~
あぁ～！　はじめまして おじいちゃんですよ～！
There are people who are waiting to that place where I was born.
＜あそこに　自分が生まれるのを 待ってくれてる人がいる＞
A~ he's lively!
あ～　元気　元気。
I want to go back to that place I was before.
＜あぁ　早く　あそこに帰ろう＞
Mitsuko?
ミツコか？
Welcome back
おかえり。
I know that people will eventually die.
＜人は死ぬけど続く＞
For what?
＜何のために？＞
Another person will be born next,
＜次に生まれて来る人に→
And then someone will say "welcome”
「ようこそ」と　いうために＞
And "Welcome back home".
＜「おかえり」と→
will be raised to a place where he can call home.
いってあげられる場所を つくるために＞
From there,
＜そこから→
Someone will say "be safe" and be sent off.
「いってらっしゃい」と 送り出してあげるために＞
"Be safe"
「はい　いってらっしゃい」。 「おう」。
"Be safe when you go to Canada~"
カナダに　いってらっしゃ～い！
This is Canada~ Stop it now
カナダで～す。 もういいって。
The bully is coming~
いじめて来ま～す。 フフ。
I'm embarrassed~
照れてま～す。 ウフフ…。
Goodbye
（月子の声）　さようなら。
Year 2010
２０１０年。
Hmm?
あ～！　ん？
Henshin!
ヘンシン！
Reset
リセット。
I'm home!
ただいま～！
Now I know..
＜どこに行きたいのか→
where will go
今　分かった＞
I..
＜俺は→
want to go back.
帰りたいんだ＞
I'm going to miss Q10 when I go back.
＜懐かしいＱ１０へ 帰って行きたいんだ＞
Welcome back home Kyuto.
＜Ｑ１０　おかえり＞
And I'm home.
＜そして　ただいま＞
The soundtrack CD of this drama
このドラマの サウンドトラックＣＤを→
Will be given to 50 lucky winners
抽選で　５０名の方に プレゼントいたします。
Please send in your postcard to the address shown
ご覧のあて先まで ハガキでご応募ください。
We will look forward to it
お待ちしているだよ。